[
    {
        "question": "إِذَا",
        "answer": "when",
        "pcklId": "399",
        "rootWordId": 27,
        "tlit": "idhā",
        "frequency": "409",
        "surahnum": "96",
        "ayahnum": "10",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " عَبْدًا إِذَا صَلَّىٰ",
        "rootWord": "إِذَا",
        "rootWordType": "nominal",
        "wazn": "إِذَا",
        "waznEnglish": "when",
        "waznTlit": "idhā",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Time adverb)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الَّذِي",
        "answer": "the One Who",
        "pcklId": "1426",
        "rootWordId": 59,
        "tlit": "alladhī",
        "frequency": "1464",
        "surahnum": "96",
        "ayahnum": "1",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " اقْرَأْ بِاسْمِ رَبِّكَ الَّذِي خَلَقَ",
        "rootWord": "ٱلَّذِى",
        "rootWordType": "nominal",
        "wazn": "ٱلَّذِى",
        "waznEnglish": "who, which, that",
        "waznTlit": "alladhī",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Relative pronoun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الَّذِي",
        "answer": "The One Who",
        "pcklId": "1427",
        "rootWordId": 59,
        "tlit": "alladhī",
        "frequency": "1464",
        "surahnum": "96",
        "ayahnum": "4",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " الَّذِي عَلَّمَ بِالْقَلَمِ",
        "rootWord": "ٱلَّذِى",
        "rootWordType": "nominal",
        "wazn": "ٱلَّذِى",
        "waznEnglish": "who, which, that",
        "waznTlit": "alladhī",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Relative pronoun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الَّذِي",
        "answer": "the one who",
        "pcklId": "1428",
        "rootWordId": 59,
        "tlit": "alladhī",
        "frequency": "1464",
        "surahnum": "96",
        "ayahnum": "9",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " أَرَأَيْتَ الَّذِي يَنْهَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ٱلَّذِى",
        "rootWordType": "nominal",
        "wazn": "ٱلَّذِى",
        "waznEnglish": "who, which, that",
        "waznTlit": "alladhī",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Relative pronoun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "اللَّهَ",
        "answer": "Allah",
        "pcklId": "2837",
        "rootWordId": 61,
        "tlit": "l-laha",
        "frequency": "2851",
        "surahnum": "96",
        "ayahnum": "14",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " أَلَمْ يَعْلَمْ بِأَنَّ اللَّهَ يَرَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "أ ل ه",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ٱللَّه",
        "waznEnglish": "Allah",
        "waznTlit": "allah",
        "waznType": "Proper noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "إِلَىٰ",
        "answer": "to",
        "pcklId": "741",
        "rootWordId": 63,
        "tlit": "ilā",
        "frequency": "742",
        "surahnum": "96",
        "ayahnum": "8",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّ إِلَىٰ رَبِّكَ الرُّجْعَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "إِلَىٰ",
        "rootWordType": "preposition",
        "wazn": "إِلَىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "to, toward, until",
        "waznTlit": "ilā",
        "waznType": "Preposition"
    },
    {
        "question": "أَمَرَ",
        "answer": "he enjoins",
        "pcklId": "75",
        "rootWordId": 69,
        "tlit": "amara",
        "frequency": "248",
        "surahnum": "96",
        "ayahnum": "12",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " أَوْ أَمَرَ بِالتَّقْوَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "أ م ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَمَرَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to order, to command",
        "waznTlit": "amara",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْإِنْسَانَ",
        "answer": "man",
        "pcklId": "89",
        "rootWordId": 78,
        "tlit": "l-insāna",
        "frequency": "97",
        "surahnum": "96",
        "ayahnum": "2",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " خَلَقَ الْإِنْسَانَ مِنْ عَلَقٍ",
        "rootWord": "أ ن س",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "إِنسَٰن",
        "waznEnglish": "you perceive",
        "waznTlit": "insān",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْإِنْسَانَ",
        "answer": "man",
        "pcklId": "90",
        "rootWordId": 78,
        "tlit": "l-insāna",
        "frequency": "97",
        "surahnum": "96",
        "ayahnum": "5",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " عَلَّمَ الْإِنْسَانَ مَا لَمْ يَعْلَمْ",
        "rootWord": "أ ن س",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "إِنسَٰن",
        "waznEnglish": "you perceive",
        "waznTlit": "insān",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْإِنْسَانَ",
        "answer": "man",
        "pcklId": "91",
        "rootWordId": 78,
        "tlit": "l-insāna",
        "frequency": "97",
        "surahnum": "96",
        "ayahnum": "6",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " كَلَّا إِنَّ الْإِنْسَانَ لَيَطْغَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "أ ن س",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "إِنسَٰن",
        "waznEnglish": "you perceive",
        "waznTlit": "insān",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "خَاطِئَةٍ",
        "answer": "sinful",
        "pcklId": "15",
        "rootWordId": 417,
        "tlit": "khāṭi-atin",
        "frequency": "22",
        "surahnum": "96",
        "ayahnum": "16",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " نَاصِيَةٍ كَاذِبَةٍ خَاطِئَةٍ",
        "rootWord": "خ ط أ",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "خَاطِئَة",
        "waznEnglish": "we err",
        "waznTlit": "khāṭi-at",
        "waznType": "Active participle (Adjective)"
    },
    {
        "question": "خَلَقَ",
        "answer": "created ",
        "pcklId": "181",
        "rootWordId": 431,
        "tlit": "khalaqa",
        "frequency": "261",
        "surahnum": "96",
        "ayahnum": "1",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " اقْرَأْ بِاسْمِ رَبِّكَ الَّذِي خَلَقَ",
        "rootWord": "خ ل ق",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "خَلَقَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to create",
        "waznTlit": "khalaqa",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "خَلَقَ",
        "answer": "He created",
        "pcklId": "182",
        "rootWordId": 431,
        "tlit": "khalaqa",
        "frequency": "261",
        "surahnum": "96",
        "ayahnum": "2",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " خَلَقَ الْإِنْسَانَ مِنْ عَلَقٍ",
        "rootWord": "خ ل ق",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "خَلَقَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to create",
        "waznTlit": "khalaqa",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "فَلْيَدْعُ",
        "answer": "Then let him call",
        "pcklId": "168",
        "rootWordId": 474,
        "tlit": "falyadʿu",
        "frequency": "212",
        "surahnum": "96",
        "ayahnum": "17",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " فَلْيَدْعُ نَادِيَهُ",
        "rootWord": "د ع و",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "دَعَا",
        "waznEnglish": "to call, to invite, to pray",
        "waznTlit": "daʿā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "سَنَدْعُ",
        "answer": "We will call",
        "pcklId": "169",
        "rootWordId": 474,
        "tlit": "sanadʿu",
        "frequency": "212",
        "surahnum": "96",
        "ayahnum": "18",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " سَنَدْعُ الزَّبَانِيَةَ",
        "rootWord": "د ع و",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "دَعَا",
        "waznEnglish": "to call, to invite, to pray",
        "waznTlit": "daʿā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "رَآهُ",
        "answer": "he sees himself",
        "pcklId": "259",
        "rootWordId": 523,
        "tlit": "raāhu",
        "frequency": "328",
        "surahnum": "96",
        "ayahnum": "7",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " أَنْ رَآهُ اسْتَغْنَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ر أ ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "رَءَا",
        "waznEnglish": "to see",
        "waznTlit": "raā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "أَرَأَيْتَ",
        "answer": "Have you seen",
        "pcklId": "260",
        "rootWordId": 523,
        "tlit": "ara-ayta",
        "frequency": "328",
        "surahnum": "96",
        "ayahnum": "9",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " أَرَأَيْتَ الَّذِي يَنْهَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ر أ ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "رَءَا",
        "waznEnglish": "to see",
        "waznTlit": "raā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "أَرَأَيْتَ",
        "answer": "Have you seen",
        "pcklId": "261",
        "rootWordId": 523,
        "tlit": "ara-ayta",
        "frequency": "328",
        "surahnum": "96",
        "ayahnum": "11",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " أَرَأَيْتَ إِنْ كَانَ عَلَى الْهُدَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ر أ ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "رَءَا",
        "waznEnglish": "to see",
        "waznTlit": "raā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "أَرَأَيْتَ",
        "answer": "Have you seen",
        "pcklId": "262",
        "rootWordId": 523,
        "tlit": "ara-ayta",
        "frequency": "328",
        "surahnum": "96",
        "ayahnum": "13",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " أَرَأَيْتَ إِنْ كَذَّبَ وَتَوَلَّىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ر أ ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "رَءَا",
        "waznEnglish": "to see",
        "waznTlit": "raā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "يَرَىٰ",
        "answer": "sees",
        "pcklId": "263",
        "rootWordId": 523,
        "tlit": "yarā",
        "frequency": "328",
        "surahnum": "96",
        "ayahnum": "14",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " أَلَمْ يَعْلَمْ بِأَنَّ اللَّهَ يَرَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ر أ ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "رَءَا",
        "waznEnglish": "to see",
        "waznTlit": "raā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "رَبِّكَ",
        "answer": "(of) your Lord",
        "pcklId": "960",
        "rootWordId": 524,
        "tlit": "rabbika",
        "frequency": "980",
        "surahnum": "96",
        "ayahnum": "1",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " اقْرَأْ بِاسْمِ رَبِّكَ الَّذِي خَلَقَ",
        "rootWord": "ر ب ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "رَبّ",
        "waznEnglish": "the Lord",
        "waznTlit": "rabb",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَرَبُّكَ",
        "answer": "and your Lord",
        "pcklId": "961",
        "rootWordId": 524,
        "tlit": "warabbuka",
        "frequency": "980",
        "surahnum": "96",
        "ayahnum": "3",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " اقْرَأْ وَرَبُّكَ الْأَكْرَمُ",
        "rootWord": "ر ب ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "رَبّ",
        "waznEnglish": "the Lord",
        "waznTlit": "rabb",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "رَبِّكَ",
        "answer": "your Lord",
        "pcklId": "962",
        "rootWordId": 524,
        "tlit": "rabbika",
        "frequency": "980",
        "surahnum": "96",
        "ayahnum": "8",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّ إِلَىٰ رَبِّكَ الرُّجْعَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ر ب ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "رَبّ",
        "waznEnglish": "the Lord",
        "waznTlit": "rabb",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "الرُّجْعَىٰ",
        "answer": "(is) the return",
        "pcklId": "83",
        "rootWordId": 536,
        "tlit": "l-ruj'ʿā",
        "frequency": "104",
        "surahnum": "96",
        "ayahnum": "8",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّ إِلَىٰ رَبِّكَ الرُّجْعَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ر ج ع",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "رُّجْعَىٰٓ",
        "waznEnglish": "[they] will not return",
        "waznTlit": "ruj'ʿā",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "الزَّبَانِيَةَ",
        "answer": "the Angels of Hell",
        "pcklId": "0",
        "rootWordId": 610,
        "tlit": "l-zabāniyata",
        "frequency": "1",
        "surahnum": "96",
        "ayahnum": "18",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " سَنَدْعُ الزَّبَانِيَةَ",
        "rootWord": "ز ب ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ز ب ن",
        "waznEnglish": "the Angels of Hell",
        "waznTlit": "zāy bā nūn",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَاسْجُدْ",
        "answer": "But prostrate",
        "pcklId": "34",
        "rootWordId": 659,
        "tlit": "wa-us'jud",
        "frequency": "92",
        "surahnum": "96",
        "ayahnum": "19",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " كَلَّا لَا تُطِعْهُ وَاسْجُدْ وَاقْتَرِبْ",
        "rootWord": "س ج د",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "سَجَدَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to prostrate",
        "waznTlit": "sajada",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "لَنَسْفَعًا",
        "answer": "surely We will drag him",
        "pcklId": "0",
        "rootWordId": 696,
        "tlit": "lanasfaʿan",
        "frequency": "1",
        "surahnum": "96",
        "ayahnum": "15",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " كَلَّا لَئِنْ لَمْ يَنْتَهِ لَنَسْفَعًا بِالنَّاصِيَةِ",
        "rootWord": "س ف ع",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "س ف ع",
        "waznEnglish": "to drag",
        "waznTlit": "sīn fā ʿayn",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "بِاسْمِ",
        "answer": "in (the) name",
        "pcklId": "46",
        "rootWordId": 726,
        "tlit": "bi-is'mi",
        "frequency": "381",
        "surahnum": "96",
        "ayahnum": "1",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " اقْرَأْ بِاسْمِ رَبِّكَ الَّذِي خَلَقَ",
        "rootWord": "س م و",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ٱسْم",
        "waznEnglish": "[I] (have) named her",
        "waznTlit": "is'm",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "صَلَّىٰ",
        "answer": "he prays",
        "pcklId": "10",
        "rootWordId": 857,
        "tlit": "ṣallā",
        "frequency": "99",
        "surahnum": "96",
        "ayahnum": "10",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " عَبْدًا إِذَا صَلَّىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ص ل و",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "صَلَّىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "to pray, to bless",
        "waznTlit": "ṣallā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form II)"
    },
    {
        "question": "لَيَطْغَىٰ",
        "answer": "surely transgresses",
        "pcklId": "11",
        "rootWordId": 913,
        "tlit": "layaṭghā",
        "frequency": "39",
        "surahnum": "96",
        "ayahnum": "6",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " كَلَّا إِنَّ الْإِنْسَانَ لَيَطْغَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ط غ ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "طَغَىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "to transgress, to overflow",
        "waznTlit": "ṭaghā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "تُطِعْهُ",
        "answer": "obey him",
        "pcklId": "74",
        "rootWordId": 931,
        "tlit": "tuṭiʿ'hu",
        "frequency": "129",
        "surahnum": "96",
        "ayahnum": "19",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " كَلَّا لَا تُطِعْهُ وَاسْجُدْ وَاقْتَرِبْ",
        "rootWord": "ط و ع",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَطَاعَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to obey",
        "waznTlit": "aṭāʿa",
        "waznType": "Verb (form IV)"
    },
    {
        "question": "عَبْدًا",
        "answer": "A slave",
        "pcklId": "263",
        "rootWordId": 948,
        "tlit": "ʿabdan",
        "frequency": "275",
        "surahnum": "96",
        "ayahnum": "10",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " عَبْدًا إِذَا صَلَّىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ع ب د",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عَبْد",
        "waznEnglish": "we worship",
        "waznTlit": "ʿabd",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "عَلَقٍ",
        "answer": "a clinging substance",
        "pcklId": "0",
        "rootWordId": 1015,
        "tlit": "ʿalaqin",
        "frequency": "7",
        "surahnum": "96",
        "ayahnum": "2",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " خَلَقَ الْإِنْسَانَ مِنْ عَلَقٍ",
        "rootWord": "ع ل ق",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عَلَق",
        "waznEnglish": "a clinging substance",
        "waznTlit": "ʿalaq",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "يَعْلَمْ",
        "answer": "he knew",
        "pcklId": "376",
        "rootWordId": 1016,
        "tlit": "yaʿlam",
        "frequency": "854",
        "surahnum": "96",
        "ayahnum": "5",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " عَلَّمَ الْإِنْسَانَ مَا لَمْ يَعْلَمْ",
        "rootWord": "ع ل م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عَلِمَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to know",
        "waznTlit": "ʿalima",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "يَعْلَمْ",
        "answer": "he know",
        "pcklId": "377",
        "rootWordId": 1016,
        "tlit": "yaʿlam",
        "frequency": "854",
        "surahnum": "96",
        "ayahnum": "14",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " أَلَمْ يَعْلَمْ بِأَنَّ اللَّهَ يَرَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ع ل م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عَلِمَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to know",
        "waznTlit": "ʿalima",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "عَلَّمَ",
        "answer": "taught",
        "pcklId": "421",
        "rootWordId": 1016,
        "tlit": "ʿallama",
        "frequency": "854",
        "surahnum": "96",
        "ayahnum": "4",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " الَّذِي عَلَّمَ بِالْقَلَمِ",
        "rootWord": "ع ل م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عَلَّمَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to teach",
        "waznTlit": "ʿallama",
        "waznType": "Verb (form II)"
    },
    {
        "question": "عَلَّمَ",
        "answer": "Taught",
        "pcklId": "422",
        "rootWordId": 1016,
        "tlit": "ʿallama",
        "frequency": "854",
        "surahnum": "96",
        "ayahnum": "5",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " عَلَّمَ الْإِنْسَانَ مَا لَمْ يَعْلَمْ",
        "rootWord": "ع ل م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عَلَّمَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to teach",
        "waznTlit": "ʿallama",
        "waznType": "Verb (form II)"
    },
    {
        "question": "اسْتَغْنَىٰ",
        "answer": "self-sufficient",
        "pcklId": "46",
        "rootWordId": 1086,
        "tlit": "is'taghnā",
        "frequency": "73",
        "surahnum": "96",
        "ayahnum": "7",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " أَنْ رَآهُ اسْتَغْنَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "غ ن ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ٱسْتَغْنَىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "to be self",
        "waznTlit": "is'taghnā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form X)"
    },
    {
        "question": "اقْرَأْ",
        "answer": "Read",
        "pcklId": "14",
        "rootWordId": 1186,
        "tlit": "iq'ra",
        "frequency": "88",
        "surahnum": "96",
        "ayahnum": "1",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " اقْرَأْ بِاسْمِ رَبِّكَ الَّذِي خَلَقَ",
        "rootWord": "ق ر أ",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "قَرَأَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to read, to recite",
        "waznTlit": "qara-a",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "اقْرَأْ",
        "answer": "Read",
        "pcklId": "15",
        "rootWordId": 1186,
        "tlit": "iq'ra",
        "frequency": "88",
        "surahnum": "96",
        "ayahnum": "3",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " اقْرَأْ وَرَبُّكَ الْأَكْرَمُ",
        "rootWord": "ق ر أ",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "قَرَأَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to read, to recite",
        "waznTlit": "qara-a",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَاقْتَرِبْ",
        "answer": "and draw near (to Allah)",
        "pcklId": "20",
        "rootWordId": 1187,
        "tlit": "wa-iq'tarib",
        "frequency": "96",
        "surahnum": "96",
        "ayahnum": "19",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " كَلَّا لَا تُطِعْهُ وَاسْجُدْ وَاقْتَرِبْ",
        "rootWord": "ق ر ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ٱقْتَرَبَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to approach, to go near",
        "waznTlit": "iq'taraba",
        "waznType": "Verb (form VIII)"
    },
    {
        "question": "بِالْقَلَمِ",
        "answer": "by the pen",
        "pcklId": "3",
        "rootWordId": 1226,
        "tlit": "bil-qalami",
        "frequency": "4",
        "surahnum": "96",
        "ayahnum": "4",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " الَّذِي عَلَّمَ بِالْقَلَمِ",
        "rootWord": "ق ل م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ق ل م",
        "waznEnglish": "their pens",
        "waznTlit": "qāf lām mīm",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "كَذَّبَ",
        "answer": "he denies",
        "pcklId": "185",
        "rootWordId": 1263,
        "tlit": "kadhaba",
        "frequency": "282",
        "surahnum": "96",
        "ayahnum": "13",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " أَرَأَيْتَ إِنْ كَذَّبَ وَتَوَلَّىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ك ذ ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كَذَّبَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to deny, to reject",
        "waznTlit": "kadhaba",
        "waznType": "Verb (form II)"
    },
    {
        "question": "كَاذِبَةٍ",
        "answer": "lying",
        "pcklId": "256",
        "rootWordId": 1263,
        "tlit": "kādhibatin",
        "frequency": "282",
        "surahnum": "96",
        "ayahnum": "16",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " نَاصِيَةٍ كَاذِبَةٍ خَاطِئَةٍ",
        "rootWord": "ك ذ ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كَٰذِب",
        "waznEnglish": "[they] lie",
        "waznTlit": "kādhib",
        "waznType": "Active participle (Adjective)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْأَكْرَمُ",
        "answer": "(is) the Most Generous",
        "pcklId": "6",
        "rootWordId": 1267,
        "tlit": "l-akramu",
        "frequency": "47",
        "surahnum": "96",
        "ayahnum": "3",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " اقْرَأْ وَرَبُّكَ الْأَكْرَمُ",
        "rootWord": "ك ر م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَكْرَم",
        "waznEnglish": "You have honored",
        "waznTlit": "akram",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Adjective)"
    },
    {
        "question": "كَانَ",
        "answer": "he is",
        "pcklId": "1352",
        "rootWordId": 1305,
        "tlit": "kāna",
        "frequency": "1390",
        "surahnum": "96",
        "ayahnum": "11",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " أَرَأَيْتَ إِنْ كَانَ عَلَى الْهُدَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ك و ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كَانَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to be",
        "waznTlit": "kāna",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "نَادِيَهُ",
        "answer": "his associates",
        "pcklId": "47",
        "rootWordId": 1455,
        "tlit": "nādiyahu",
        "frequency": "53",
        "surahnum": "96",
        "ayahnum": "17",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " فَلْيَدْعُ نَادِيَهُ",
        "rootWord": "ن د و",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "نَادِي",
        "waznEnglish": "And they called one another",
        "waznTlit": "nādī",
        "waznType": "Active participle"
    },
    {
        "question": "بِالنَّاصِيَةِ",
        "answer": "by the forelock",
        "pcklId": "1",
        "rootWordId": 1479,
        "tlit": "bil-nāṣiyati",
        "frequency": "4",
        "surahnum": "96",
        "ayahnum": "15",
        "wordnum": "6",
        "arabicAyah": " كَلَّا لَئِنْ لَمْ يَنْتَهِ لَنَسْفَعًا بِالنَّاصِيَةِ",
        "rootWord": "ن ص ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "نَاصِيَة",
        "waznEnglish": "of its forelock",
        "waznTlit": "nāṣiyat",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "نَاصِيَةٍ",
        "answer": "A forelock",
        "pcklId": "2",
        "rootWordId": 1479,
        "tlit": "nāṣiyatin",
        "frequency": "4",
        "surahnum": "96",
        "ayahnum": "16",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " نَاصِيَةٍ كَاذِبَةٍ خَاطِئَةٍ",
        "rootWord": "ن ص ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "نَاصِيَة",
        "waznEnglish": "of its forelock",
        "waznTlit": "nāṣiyat",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "يَنْهَىٰ",
        "answer": "forbids",
        "pcklId": "31",
        "rootWordId": 1526,
        "tlit": "yanhā",
        "frequency": "56",
        "surahnum": "96",
        "ayahnum": "9",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " أَرَأَيْتَ الَّذِي يَنْهَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ن ه ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "نَهَىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "to forbid",
        "waznTlit": "nahā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "يَنْتَهِ",
        "answer": "he desists",
        "pcklId": "48",
        "rootWordId": 1526,
        "tlit": "yantahi",
        "frequency": "56",
        "surahnum": "96",
        "ayahnum": "15",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " كَلَّا لَئِنْ لَمْ يَنْتَهِ لَنَسْفَعًا بِالنَّاصِيَةِ",
        "rootWord": "ن ه ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ٱنتَهَىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "to refrain, to cease, to desist",
        "waznTlit": "intahā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form VIII)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْهُدَىٰ",
        "answer": "[the] guidance",
        "pcklId": "275",
        "rootWordId": 1547,
        "tlit": "l-hudā",
        "frequency": "316",
        "surahnum": "96",
        "ayahnum": "11",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " أَرَأَيْتَ إِنْ كَانَ عَلَى الْهُدَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ه د ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "هُدًى",
        "waznEnglish": "Guide us",
        "waznTlit": "hudan",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "بِالتَّقْوَىٰ",
        "answer": "[of the] righteousness",
        "pcklId": "200",
        "rootWordId": 1641,
        "tlit": "bil-taqwā",
        "frequency": "258",
        "surahnum": "96",
        "ayahnum": "12",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " أَوْ أَمَرَ بِالتَّقْوَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "و ق ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "تَقْوَى",
        "waznEnglish": "and save us",
        "waznTlit": "taqwā",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَتَوَلَّىٰ",
        "answer": "and turns away",
        "pcklId": "108",
        "rootWordId": 1648,
        "tlit": "watawallā",
        "frequency": "232",
        "surahnum": "96",
        "ayahnum": "13",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " أَرَأَيْتَ إِنْ كَذَّبَ وَتَوَلَّىٰ",
        "rootWord": "و ل ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "تَوَلَّىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "to turn",
        "waznTlit": "tawallā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form V)"
    }
]